Guide to the Gabriel Astruc papers
The New York Public Library. Jerome Robbins Dance Division.
- Series II: Subject files
  - Sub-series I - People, 13 folders
    - Romola Nijinsky - Astruc, 1925 (Reel 1, Index.106 106)
    - Ida Rubinstein (Reel 1, Index.107 107)
      Correspondence from her lawyers deChauveron and Pequin
    - Ida Rubinstein letters (Reel 1, Index.108 108)
    - Ida Rubinstein telegrams (Reel 1, Index.109 109)
    - Ida Rubinstein miscellaneous (Reel 1, Index.110 110)
      Includes biographical note, a drawing by Etlin, a sonnet by Ochse and miscellaneous letters
    - Trouhanova letters, 1906 - 1913 (Reel 1, Index.111 111)
    - Trouhanova letters, n.d. (Reel 1, Index.112 112)
    - Trouhanova telegrams (Reel 1, Index.113 113)
    - Trouhanova letters to or about Trouhanova, and miscellaneous receipts and orders (Reel 1, Index.114 114)
  - Sub-series II: Geographic Subject Files, 6 folders
    Correspondence and miscellaneous items.
    Items grouped around a geographical area: Deauville, Germany and Italy, Lyons and Marseilles. Correspondence is further subdivided alphabetically by writer and placed in chronological order under each writer's name.
    - Deauville correspondence from Eugegrave;ne Cornuche (Reel 1, Index.115 115)
    - Deauville correspondence, D-R (Reel 1, Index.116 116)
    - Deauville finance and miscellaneous (Reel 1, Index.117 117)
    - Germany and Italy (Reel 1, Index.118 118)
    - Lyons and Marseilles correspondence, A - D (Reel 1, Index.119 119)
    - Lyons and Marseilles correspondence, S - V, and clippings (Reel 1, Index.120 120)
- Series III: Clippings, Programs and Announcements, 1906-1914; 3 folders
  Clippings are in original chronological arrangement, and are primarily from 1911. Programs and announcement are placed in chronological order.
  - Clippings, 1911,1913 (Reel 1, Index.121 121-122)
  - Programs and announcements, 1906 -1914 (Reel 1, Index.123 123)